A Finding Aid to the Hiram Powers Papers, 1819-1953, bulk 1835-1883, in the Archives of American Art AAA.powehira
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, circa 1860s-1900, 1927, 1932; Series 6; (Box 10-13, 16, OV 17; 1.8 linear feet)
  - Glass Plate Negatives
    - Hiram Powers, circa 1870s (Box 13)
      2 glass plate negatives
    - Elizabeth Powers, circa 1870s (Box 13)
    - Two Men in a Car, circa 1900 (Box 13)
      4 glass plate negatives
    - Unidentified Portraits, circa 1870s (Box 12)
    - Unidentified Portraits, circa 1870s (Box 13)
    - Outdoor Carnival, circa 1870s (Box 13)
    - Sculpture in Powers Studio, circa 1870s (Box 13)
    - Sculpture, circa 1870s (Box 12)
      25 glass plate negatives
  - Oversized Photograph Portraits of Hiram Powers, circa 1860s-1870s; (Scanned with Box 10, Folders 59-60) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 1)
  - Oversized Photographs of Hiram Powers Studio, circa 1860s; (Scanned with Box 10, Folder 65) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 2)
  - Oversized Photographs of Artwork by Hiram Powers, circa late-1800s; (See also Box 11, Folders 12-13; not scanned) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 3)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1860s-1880s, 1932; (Scanned with Box 11, Folder 17) (Box 15 (sol), Folder 4)
  - Oversized Photograph Album belonging to Louisa Powers Ibbotson, 1927; (Scanned with Box 11, Folder 19) (Box 16 (sol), Folder 5)
  - Oversized Posters of Photographs by Longworth Powers, circa 1860s-late-1800s; (Scanned with Box 11, Folder 18) (Box OV 17)
- Artwork, 1860, mid-1800s; Series 7; (Box 11; 4 folders)
  This series contains three drawings by Hiram Powers, including a caricature of the artist Miner Kellogg, a caricature of a "Bust of a Florentine done by one of Bartolini's pupils," and a drawing of his servant "Old Annuziata". Also found is a pencil drawing, possibly by Miner K. Kellogg, of his Powers' residence in Ohio, and an ink drawing of the floor plan of the Poggio Imperiale. This series also includes a drawing of "Alexr [ sic] Drake singing Love and Sausage". The legibility of the signature is unclear, but it may have been drawn by the Cincinnati sculptor, Thomas Dow Jones.
  - Caricature and Portrait Drawings by Hiram Powers, circa mid-1800s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 20)
  - Drawing of "First Residence of Hiram Powers in Ohio,", circa mid-1800s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 21)
  - Floor Plan of Poggio Imperiale, circa mid-1800s (Box 11 (hol), Folder 22)
  - Drawing by T. Jones, 1860 (Box 11 (hol), Folder 23)
- Scrapbooks and Albums, 1847-1876; Series 8; (Box 14; 3 folders)
  This series contains two albums and a scrapbook compiled by members of the Powers family. Included is a scrapbook containing news clippings regarding the American tour and public response to Hiram Powers' sculpture "Greek Slave" and several notices of his death in 1873. Also found is an album presented to Louisa Powers from her mother that contains autographed poems and quotations from several notable authors, including Robert and Elizabeth Barrett Browning, Bayard Taylor, Thomas Buchanan Read, William Cullen Bryant, and the Trollope family. Another album found here, possibly belonging to Louisa Powers, contains three pencil drawings by Preston Powers, poetry, and dried flowers collected on travels during 1867.
  - Scrapbook, "Notices of Powers' Work,", 1847-1849, 1873-1876 (Box 14 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Album of Autographed Poetry, 1858-1861 (Box 14 (hol), Folder 2)
  - "Album,", 1855, 1861-1867 (Box 14 (hol), Folder 3)